so let's look at the solution to a RAID
one quiz we have a raid 1 array with two
disks a single disk in this array is a
200 gigabyte disk with a throughput of
10 megabytes per second and an entity f
of a hundred thousand hours and when a
disk fails we replace it and it takes us
24 hours to do that so in a two disc
RAID one the data capacity is the same
as for one disk that's because both
disks are storing exactly the same data
which allows us to survive the failure
of one disk the throughput when we are
reading is twice the throughput of a
single disk because we can issue reads
to both disks at the same time but when
we are writing we are writing to both
disks at once so the throughput for
writing is only 10 megabytes per second
if half of the requests are reads and
the other half of the requests are
writes then in any given second we will
be spending one third of a second on the
reads and we will be spending two-thirds
of the second on the writes that way we
get to do the same number of reads and
writes per second it's just that the
reads are twice as fast so they take
half the time of the writes in that same
second in the one third of a second that
we've been doing reads we were getting a
20 megabyte per second throughput
because we were using both disks in the
two-thirds of the second when we were
doing writes we were getting only 10
megabytes per second so overall during
this one second
using the raid 1 array we ended up
getting a true put of 40 over 3
megabytes which gives us a throughput of
13 and a third megabytes per second
because in one second we managed to
access 40 over 3 megabytes so the answer
here is 13.33 note that the throughput
is not 15 megabytes per second which is
what we would get if we simply average
the read throughput and the right true
put we would get in this array because
if we did this we are assuming that for
half a second we are reading and then
for half a second we are
and thus we get 15 megabytes read and
written in a second but if for half a
second we read and for half a second we
write we end up reading twice the amount
of data that we would for writes so if
the workload is 50/50 in terms of number
of accesses then it's not also 50/50 in
terms of time spent on reads and time
spent on writes reads are faster thus we
spend less time on them which is why
again the throughput is not 15 megabytes
per second and finally let us figure out
the MTTF for the entire raid 1 array the
MTTF of a whole raid 1 array with two
disks we said is equal to the MTTF of a
single disk divided by 2 so this is how
long we have to operate with two disks
until one of the disks fails and now
each time we have a one disk failure we
need to repair it and we said that the
number of times we can try a repair
until we finally experience a failure of
the second disk during the repair of the
first disk is empty the F of one disk
divided by the MTTR of the disk so this
first factor would be 50,000 hours the
second factor is the ratio of the time
to failure and the time to repair and
when we divide these two we get four
thousand one hundred sixty six point six
six six etc so this is how many times
can we try a repair while a single disk
is working until we finally experience a
repair in which the working disk also
fails and when we multiply this out we
get 208 million three hundred 33333
hours so this is a huge amount of time
compared to the original disks mdtf
as you can see rate one dramatically
improves reliability this time is about
11 years this time is about 24,000 years
so as you can see the reliability has
improved from being able to expect data
loss every about ten years to something
that goes into tens of thousands of
years